Name: ALEX KIMATHI MURITHI

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-kimathi/

Email: <u>kimathialex54@gmail.com</u>

Tel: +254708353465

GitHub: https://github.com/Alexkimathi

Portfolio website: http://survey-3e3p.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

As a Full-Stack Web Developer with over 3 years of experience in technologies like Java, Node.js, React, and Typescript, I am seeking a challenging role in a dynamic organization. I have a strong understanding of HTML, CSS with SCSS, and JavaScript, and experience with JavaScript component libraries. Additionally, I have experience with Typescript and responsive user interfaces for a wide range of devices and browsers. I have worked with Git and other version control systems, and I am aware of SEO best practices and accessibility in all aspects of my work. I have a strong understanding of web performance in complex user interfaces and the ability to interact with UX, designers, and server-side developers. I hold a Bachelor's degree in Information Technology

PERSONAL SKILLS

- > Proficient in MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), Ruby on Rails and java
- Extensive experience in Typescript, GraphQL, React.js, and Redux.
- > Strong knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, SQL, JavaScript, and SaaS.
- Familiarity with Kotlin and Jira Board for project collaborations.
- > Proficient in Agile software methodology.
- Skilled in version control systems like Git.
- > Effective communication and collaboration skills.

PROJECT SUMMARY

BUK-A-MEAL –A web app for ordering food from local restaurants

Frontend GitHub link: https://github.com/Alexkimathi/buk-a-meal-frontend

Backend GitHub link: https://github.com/Alexkimathi/buk-a-meal-backend

NOTE-APP

A notes app with CRUD operations to practice creating API endpoints with Node.js

Used Typescript for the frontend

GitHub link: https://github.com/Alexkimathi/Mern-note-app

EXPERIENCE

1. Software Developer, Cal wide solutions Nairobi Kenya

Sep 2021 – December 2022

- Collaborated with cross-functional product teams to develop and implement new features and solutions
- > Utilized Agile methodologies to ensure efficient and transparent development processes
- > Proposed and defended technical solutions to enhance product functionality and user experience
- > Collaborated with peers to address complex technical challenges and optimize software performance
- > Contributed to code reviews and provided constructive feedback to enhance code quality
- Participated in unit testing and integration testing to ensure the robustness of software

2. Technical Support Representative, Basel Nairobi, Kenya

January 2023 to Date

- Worked as team member to design and implement the Microsoft Navision system
- ➤ Maintained clients systems
- Provided technical assistance to customers, troubleshooting and resolving issues related to mobile devices, network connectivity, and other telecom services.
- ➤ Effectively communicated complex technical information in a clear and understandable manner to customers with varying levels of technical knowledge.
- > Consistently achieved and exceeded performance targets for customer satisfaction, response time, and issue resolution.

EDUCATION

April 2022 – November 4th **Moringa school**

Full Stack Software Development

May 2018- Dec 2021 Dedan Kimathi University of Science and Technology.

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

REFEREES

Available upon request